Han Chooi

A: Hay Street, West Perth, WA 6005 | M: 0426 674 453 | E: tsinchooi@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/hanchooi GitHub: https://github.com/hanchooi

PROFILE

I am studying for a Master's in Information Technology and have 3 years of experience in the financial industry. Using my problem-solving skills, I have formulated solutions for business-critical issues for my past employers.

I have used my skill at distilling difficult concepts into simple explanations to present financial forecasts and discussing business plans with stakeholders to strategize business expansion. I am also confident in my ability to quickly adapt and learn new technology to develop business solutions.

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATION

Master of Information Technology
University of Western Australia, Perth, Australia

Jul 2019 – Dec 2021

GPA: 7.0

BSc Economics

University of London International Programme lead by LSE

Sep 2012 – Aug 2015

First Class Honours

Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Fundamentals Feb 2021 – Feb 2021

WORK EXPERIENCE

Bookkeeper & Office Administrator

Jan 2020 – Present

Fushang Food Services, Perth

- Recorded and processed accounts accurately and thoroughly, with attention to detail.
- Improved existing SOP to the reduce possibility of human error and enable efficient information retrieval.
- Handled communication with third parties including email, text and verbal communication.
- · Performed translation for stakeholders, demonstrating good interpersonal skills.
- Performed day to day operational task with minimal monitoring and a high level of autonomy.

Cooperative Board Member

Dec 2016 - Dec 2019

KWW Cooperative, Malaysia

- Created and implemented SOP for new business. Analysed workflow to further streamline existing SOP.
- Elected as a board member. Participated in board meetings to plan business strategy.
- Examined laws and regulations to ensure business legality and kept board members informed.
- Acquired new skills and knowledge to temporarily bridge skill gaps of the existing team.
- Brainstormed with other board members to formulate solutions for business-critical issues & problems.
- Strategised fundraising activities and raised 10 Million MYR for the Cooperative.
- Expanded new business division, hired and trained new staffs.
- Built good office culture and developed a performing team.

Financial Executive

Dec 2016 – Dec 2019

The City Group, Malaysia

- Collaborated with top executives to go over business strategy to maximise profits.
- Planned financial budget and forecasted business return to assist stakeholders in decision making.
- Presented forecast and discussed business plans with stakeholders to strategise business expansion.
- Supervised team member to ensure accurate financial records and data entries.
- Managed employees' payroll to ensure timely salary payments.
- Collaborated with auditors to produce yearly accounts.

Tutor (for Bachelor Degree) and Lecturer (for Diploma)

Sep 2015 - Dec 2016

HELP University (Malaysia)

- Taught various subjects such as Monetary Economics, Corporate Finance, Statistics and Mathematics.
- Guided students in exam strategy and answer techniques which helped improve students' results.
- Assigned to handle diploma units as a lecturer after 6 months due to good feedback from students.

LANGUAGES & DIALECTS

English: Fluent
 IELTS Overall Score: Band 8

Mandarin: Fluent

Malay, Cantonese & Hokkien: Intermediate

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES & TOOLS

- General-purpose Programming Language: Python, Java.
- Front End Web Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Web Framework : React, Vue, Flask.
- Database Language: MySQL.
- Programming Language & Tools for Statistical Computing: R, Python & Jupyter Notebook.
- Cloud Computing Platforms: AWS, Microsoft Azure.

SKILLS

- Innovative problem-solver who generate workable solutions with limited resources.
- Fast learner with excellent self-learning ability. Able to comprehend and address complex tasks.
- Actively contributing team member with the ability to motivate and inspire others.
- · Well-versed in communication and interpersonal skills which develops positive relations with colleagues.
- Equipped with leadership skills that motivate individual team members to excel in specific tasks.
- Have strong organizational skills, ability to prioritize and complete tasks with speed and accuracy.
- Able to work independently with minimal monitoring and a high level of autonomy.
- Very experienced at using Microsoft Excel, Word, & PowerPoint.
- Able to use Microsoft Excel to perform business analysis and building financial forecasts.
- Good at running statistical analysis on Jupyter Notebook.
- Excellent presentation and pitching skill.

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES & VOLUNTEERING

Treasurer (2021) May 2020 – Present

Coders for Causes

- Involved in the development of webapp and website for BFA Rescue & home2health.
- (<u>bfa-rescue-git-main-coders-for-causes.vercel.app</u>)(<u>github.com/codersforcauses/home2health</u>)

Volunteer May 2013 – Present

Tzu Chi Foundation

- Volunteered in Tzu Chi Hospital in Taiwan and Perth's aged care centre.
- Participated in Perth city cleaning on Earth Day.
- Participated in acting for stage play promoting filial piety and charity.

UniMentor Dec 2020 – Present

- Shared useful tips and information about UWA to help newcomers better adjust to living in UWA.
- Gave useful advice about study preparation and encouraged active involvement in clubs and societies.

Mentee Aug 2020 – Dec 2020

UWA Career Mentor Link

• Learned about the importance of different soft skills and body of knowledge required for different jobs.

Secretary (2016) Sep 2016 – Sep 2017

Junior Chamber International

- · Wrote agendas and minutes for weekly board meetings.
- Composed invitation letters for events and email template for getting sponsors.

REFEREES

Tina Chen Dalip Singh

Account Manager Chief Operating Officer (Juara Partners)
(Fushang Food Services) Cooperative Treasurer (KWW Cooperative)

+61 450 902 529 +60 19 - 751 2258 fushang.food@gmail.com dalipsingh@thecitygroup.com